Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 11 Month(s)

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period



Work experience in both Development and Application Support with Oracle, SQL, PLSQL, Control-M, Putty, ITRS Geneos, dbRUN Portal,



Current Designation: Senior Software Engineer

Current Company: HCL Technologies

Current Location: Chennai

Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Married

Key Skills: SQL,PLSQL,SQL Developer,Putty,Servicenow,dbRUN,DR Portal,MySQL,Application Support,production

support, Control-M, ITRS Geneos, Unix, Linux, L2, L2 Support Engineer

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Having 4.10 years Professional experience in ORACLE SQL, PLSQL, UNIX, Maintenance and Enhancement.

Working experience in Banking domain.

Primary skills include Oracle SQL and PL/SQL.

Excellent skills in creating SQL objects like Tables, Views, Sequence and Synonyms.

Worked in Constraints, DDL and DML statements.

Have Unix as secondary skills.

Working experience in Priority to do supports for solving day to day issues on 24*7 rotational shifts basics.

Highly Motivated, Excellent team player, enthusiastic, strong initiative and quick learner of new technologies.

Work Experience

HCL Technologies as Senior Software Engineer

Aug 2018 to Till Date

Understanding the scope document and providing sizing.

Creating SQL objects like Tables, Views, Sequence and Synonyms.

Worked in Constraints, DDL and DML statements.

Creating Change request for the PROD deployment.

Develop and maintain Programming Codes.

Good Knowledge on Linux Operating and commands.

Mabel Info Tech as Software Engineer

Aug 2013 to Aug 2018

Monitoring day-to-day process for different Data Loads and resolving the issues.

Monitoring the successful completion of the jobs daily which were scheduled for accurate flow of data from application.

Built complex queries using SQL.

Understanding and Troubleshooting complex customer issues on production environment as per KEDB document.

Support during Weekend for all issues, Involved in Purging activities and also batch jobs.

Sending Monthly status reports to users required.

Understanding the requirements and carrying out impact analysis.

I had monitor the system very closely and can not afford to leave the system without someone else monitoring it. It is a 24*7 job defined within a team to work in shifts.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from SAMS College Of Engineering and Technology College in 2012

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

TCS ion

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
Unix			2 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
SQL DEVELOPER			4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
PRODUCTION SUPPORT			4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)	
Application Support			4 Year(s) 6 Month(s)	
Geneos	GA4.6.0	2020	1 Year(s) 8 Month(s)	
ServiceNow	current	2020	2 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	
CONTROL-M	9.0	2020	2 Year(s) 1 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
Tamil	Proficient			
English	Proficient			

Projects

Project Title: DB-CHEQUE Client: Deutsche Bank AG

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2018 - Aug 2020 Role: Sr. Programmer Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Team Size: 11

Skill Used: SQL, PLSQL am good knowledge in writing SQL joins and sub queries.

Project Details: DB-CHEQUE is a Cheque printing system in which Deutsche Bank provides Facility to

customers like printing bank Cheques, corporate Cheques, demand draft. This cheques transformation module is used for issuance, collection,

clearance, returns of cheques. Through this module we can take a part of all cheque processing like scanning a cheque.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time